<resources>
    <string name="square">1:1</string>
    <string name="gold_vertical">1:1.618</string>
    <string name="gold_horizon">1.618:1</string>
    <string name="gold_horizon_x">2.618:1</string>

    <string name="app_name">News the Three</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="choose_category">Chọn danh mục</string>
    <string name="category">Danh mục</string>
    <string-array name="categories">
        <item>Thời sự</item>
        <item>Thế giới</item>
        <item>Pháp luật</item>
        <item>Kinh doanh</item>
        <item>Công nghệ</item>
        <item>xe</item>
        <item>Du lịch</item>
        <item>Nhịp sống trẻ</item>
        <item>Văn hóa</item>
        <item>Giải trí</item>
        <item>Thể thao</item>
        <item>Giáo dục</item>
        <item>Khoa học</item>
        <item>Sức khỏe</item>
        <item>Thư giãn</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">It\'s OPEN!</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">IT\'s WAS CLOSED! fuck</string>
    <string name="earth_content"> Tại sao tất cả mọi thứ trong Hệ Mặt Trời đều quay? Và tại sao hầu hết mọi chuyển động quay đều có cùng một hướng?
\n Điều này không thể là ngẫu nhiên được. Nhìn xuống Trái Đất từ phía trên, và bạn sẽ thấy nó quay ngược chiều kim đồng hồ. Cũng tương tự với Mặt Trời, Sao Hỏa và các hành tinh khác.
\n 4.54 tỷ năm trước, Hệ Mặt Trời của chúng ta hình thành bên trong một đám mây hydro, đám mây này khác với tinh vân Orion hay tinh vân Đại Bang với những đường ống tuyệt vời của tạo hóa.
\n Sau đó, nó cần một vài tác động, chẳng hạn như những sóng xung kích từ một siêu tân tinh gần đó, và điều này tạo ra một khu vực khí lạnh dồn vào bên trong thông qua lực hấp dẫn của chúng. Khi nó đã co lại, đám mây bắt đầu quay.
    </string>
    <string name="earth_content_2"> Hãy nghĩ về một cá thể phân tử trong đám mây Hydro. Mỗi hạt mang động lượng riêng của nó và trôi đi trong không gian. Khi những phân tử này kết hợp với phân tử khác bởi trọng lực, chúng cần phải cân bằng động lượng của mỗi hạt. Khả năng cân bằng hoàn hảo bằng 0 là có thể xảy ra, nhưng thực sự rất khó.
\n Có nghĩa là, một số trong số chúng sẽ trượt qua nhau. Giống như những người trượt băng nghệ thuật cầm tay kéo nhau để quay nhanh hơn, sự co lại của tinh vân tiền Mặt Trời với động lượng của các hạt cân bằng của nó trở nên quay nhanh hơn.
\n Đây chính là lúc bảo toàn động lượng quay bắt đầu có tác động
\n Khi Hệ Mặt Trời quay càng nhanh, nó bị dẹt ra thành một đĩa với một khu vực phình ở giữa. Chúng ta thấy cấu trúc tương tự ở khắp nơi trong vũ trụ: Hình dáng của các thiên hà, xung quanh các lỗ đen đang quay...
\n Mặt Trời hình thành từ chỗ phình ở tâm chiếc đĩa này, và các hành tinh hình thành bên ngoài. Chúng thừa hưởng chuyển động quay từ chuyển động tổng thể của bản thân Hệ Mặt Trời.
\n Trong suốt một vài trăm triệu năm, tất cả vật chất trong Hệ Mặt Trời tập trung lại với nhau thành các hành tinh, tiểu hành tinh, mặt trăng và sao chổi... Sau đó bức xạ mạnh và gió sao từ ngôi sao trẻ Mặt Trời thổi sạch những thứ còn lại khác.
\n Không có bất kỳ lực không cân bằng nào khác tác động lên chúng, nên quán tính của Mặt Trời và các hành tinh đã giữ chúng quay trong hàng tỷ năm qua.
\n Và chúng sẽ tiếp tục quay cho đến khi chúng va chạm với các vật thể khác, hàng tỷ hoặc thậm chí hàng nghìn tỷ năm sau trong tương lai.
</string>
    <string name="comment_thank">Bài viết này rất hay, cám ơn tác giả nhé!\n\n p/s: Tôi thấy người làm app này rất là đẹp chai.</string>
    <string name="n">\n</string>
    <string name="about_title">Khoa Công nghệ Phần mềm
        \nGiao tiếp người - máy
        \nSE215.I12\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="about_lecturer">
        \nGiảng viên hướng dẫn:
        \nNguyễn Công Hoan
    </string>
    <string name="about_team">
        \nNhóm 3:
        \nNguyễn Phương Nguyên - 14520601
        \nNguyễn Thanh Nam - 14520556
        \nĐinh Hoàng Khang - 14520404
        \n
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_category">CategoryActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
</resources>
